#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/lindsaymruss (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Coaching Leadership

Leadership Development

### Certifications

Organizational Learning and Development

Teaching Techniques: Developing Curriculum

Instructional Design

### Honors-Awards

Leadership Certificate Program

# Lindsay M. Russ

Strategist | People Developer | Consultant

West Bloomfield Township, Michigan, United States

## Summary

"Be the change you wish to see" - Mahatma Gandhi

With over 10 years in leadership with a focus on leadership development, I approach all situations as an opportunity to build and foster new relationships to inspire others to bring out the best in themselves. I work to help others live confidently in the intersection of leadership, wellness, and community.

I effectively lead teams through organizational changes while keeping a focus on developing the companies greatest asset - the people. My skills in building trusting relationships and my ability to take multiple perspectives, allows me to quickly analyze and create strategic plans that result in successful execution and impacts to the bottom line.

I passionately drive results using creativity and innovation to provide the best experience from beginning to end. My background in hospitality allows me to keep a client centered perspective in any role that I take on. It also ignited my passion for helping other leaders gain the confidence in their potential, through integrating wellness practices that amplify impact in their personal and professional lives.

## Experience

Rock Central
Team Leader, Training
August 2020 - August 2023 (3 years 1 month)

Strategic partner supporting Amrock business goals utilizing cross business relationships across Rocket Mortgage, Rocket Central, and technology teams. Collaborative leadership for design and development of training solutions. Experience with front and back end learning and development functions.

Business knowledge of mortgage and title processes.

Congressional Hunger Center Talent and Development Graduate Intern April 2020 - September 2020 (6 months)

I assist the Director of Training and Development with the Leadership Development Curriculum and learning and development initiatives of the Congressional Hunger Center.

- Assist with updating learning management system of the CHC
- Create engaging virtual presentations to enhance learning process and needs
- Conduct research and analysis to post surveys to make recommendations to learning plans

Renaissance Hotels
Rooms Operations Manager
December 2018 - April 2020 (1 year 5 months)
Greater New Orleans Area

As a Rooms Operations Manager at the Renaissance Arts Hotel, I was the department head and hiring manager of the front desk operations of a 219 room hotel. While managing a staff of 15 with 4 direct reports I was responsible for data analysis and strategic planning and execution to drive operational goals to meet key performance indicators. During my time, I was able to:

- Facilitate monthly market trainings of over 15 Renaissance brand new hires to enhance training and understanding of Renaissance brand and culture
- Improve on-boarding process of new hires through structured and consistent training planning and execution
- Build cross departmental relationships to effectively lead and motivate hotel employees to drive results in respective departments and as a collective

Walt Disney World
Guest Experience Manager
July 2016 - December 2018 (2 years 6 months)
Orlando, Florida Area

As a Guest Experience Manager (GEM) at Walt Disney World Parks and Resorts, I served as a Front Desk GEM for the Polynesian Villiage Resort, Custodial GEM at Magic Kingdom, and Food and Beverage GEM at Hollywood Studios where I planned and implemented effective departmental strategies to engage and inspire over 50 cast members to drive results and meet operational goals. During my time, I was able to:

- Train and lead the on-boarding of new hired cast members, providing tools and resources to ensure successful retention and decreased operational turnover
- Gain familiarity with Learning Management System(s) to assist cast members with training completions contributing to achieving top training compliance scores
- Created visual aids, presentations, and training aids to train cast members on new procedures resulting in timely training and adaption of process execution

### Education

Michigan State University
Masters, Management, Strategy, and Leadership

Crummer Graduate School of Business at Rollins College Crummer Certification in Business Management - Mini MBA

Bowling Green State University

Bachelor of Arts and Science in Journalism, Public Relations

Bowling Green State University Leadership Certificate Program, Leadership